Guide to the Foundation for Theological Education in South East Asia Records - Addendum A
Yale University Divinity School Library
Foundation for Theological Education in South East Asia Records - Addendum A
1938-2017
2010-2015
RG 180A
Yale University Divinity School Library
3.5
(10 boxes)
This collection is a continuation of the Archives of the Foundation for Theological Education in South East Asia found in Record Group No. 180. It includes historical and administrative records related to the FTESEA dating from 1938 to 2015. It also includes publications of the FTESEA, photographs, financial records, and resources from its partners and related organizations. The Foundation for Theological Education in South East Asia supports Christian theological education in South East Asia in a variety of ways including grants to institutions and projects, scholarships, consultations, and publications. Funds initially devoted to the work of Nanking Theological Seminary were expanded to theological education institutions outside of China following the closure of China to mission work in 1949. As China become more open to the West, FTESEA resumed programs supporting theological education there.
Dong nan Ya shen xue jiao yu ji jin hui
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Deposited by the FTESEA
Biographical / Historical
See earlier historical information in the finding aid for Record Group 180. The Foundation for Theological Education in South East Asia celebrated its 75th anniversary in 2012 and initiated a revisioning process that has led to structural and policy changes.
Scope and Contents
This record group is a continuation of the archives of the Foundation for Theological Education in South East Asia contained in Yale Divnity Library Record Group 180. The material primarily dates from 2010 to 2015. Earlier materials have largely been filed with the earlier record group, except as they have relevance to ongoing issues.
Series I, Administrative Records, is divided into five subseries representing the different records and committees of the FTESEA: a) Legal documents; b) Board of Trustee records; c) Executive director records; d) Strategic planning; and e) Events and reports. The administrative records include documentation of FTESEA meetings, including agendas, minutes, committee documents and reports, and executive director reports, as well as material related to strategic planning and FTESEA special events. These records provide valuable insight into the FTESEA and its administration over time.
Series II, Financial and Grant Records, includes financial records such as audits, budgets, grants, and invoices.
Series III contains publications of the FTESEA including newsletters, the Chinese Theological Review, the Nanjing Theological Review, and the FTESEA's history project, which resulted in the book titled Supporting Asian Christiantiyt's Transition from Mission to Church, A History of the Foundation for Theological Education in South East Asia by Samuel C. Pearson,.
Series IV contains materials related to the FTESEA's partners and related organizations, including documents from organizations such as the Association for Theological Education in South East Asia (ATESEA), the Nanjing Union Theological Seminary, and the World Council of Churches.
Series V includes audio and visual materials related to the FTESEA and collected materials related to FTESEA, theological education and globalization, and religion in China. Series VI includes various collected material on subjects related to the work of the FTESEA.
Arrangement
I. Administrative Records, 1938-2015
II. Financial and Grant Records, 2001-2014
III. Publications, 1984-2014
IV. Partners and Related Organizations, 1953-2015
V. Audio-Visual Materials, 2001-2012
VI. Collected Material, 2001-2011
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Religious education -- Asia; Universities and colleges -- Asia; Dong nan Ya shen xue jiao yu ji jin hui; Jinling shen xue yuan
- Administrative Records, 1938-2017; Series I
  - Legal documents
    - Historical legal documentation, 1938-2005 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Includes chronology of legal actions regarding the FTESEA, Cy Pres determinations
    - Regarding revision of constitution and registration as charitable organization, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Revised By-Laws, 2016 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Contract between FTE and H.S. Wilson, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Board of Trustee records
    - List of dates and venues of FTESEA Board meetings 1937-2006, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - FTESEA Trustees directory, 2011-2015 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - FTESEA Trustees directory, 2016-2017 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Annual meeting, 2010 October (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Annual meeting, 2011 October (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Annual meeting, 2012 September (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Annual meeting, 2013 October (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Annual meeting, 2014 October (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Annual meeting, 2015 October (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Annual meeting, 2016 October (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Annual meeting, 2017 November (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Executive Committee, 2010 October 4 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Executive Committee, 2011 May, October (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Executive Committee, 2012 May, September, December (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Executive Committee, 2013 February, October, December (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Executive Committee, 2014 August, October (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Executive Committee, 2015 August, October (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Executive Committee, 2016 July, October (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Search Committee records and correspondence, 2003-2006 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Search Committee records and contracts with H.S. Wilson - additional files provided by Benjamin Chan, 2006-2012 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Nominations Committee, 2002-2013 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Other committees and working groups, including formation of Program, Audit, Finance committees, 2013-2015 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Executive Director records
    - H.S. Wilson reports, 2010, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - H.S. Wilson report, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - H.S. Wilson report, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - H.S. Wilson report, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - H.S. Wilson reports, 2015, 2016, 2017 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence of Executive Director H.S. Wilson, 2006-2012 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence of Executive Director H.S. Wilson, 2015-2017 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Strategic planning
    - Strategic proposals for priority projects for FTESEA in the next mandate period, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Revisioning workshop report and follow-up, 2013 October 7-8 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Events and reports
    - 75th anniversary planning, program, and exhibit materials, 2011-2012 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 75th anniversary celebration: presentations by Prof. Xu Yihua, Werner Dietrich, Chen Yilu, Peter Nguyen, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 75th anniversary celebration: including DVDs of interviews with Board members, 2012 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Report of ATESEA and FTESEA visit, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Women Theological Educators and Women in Theological Movements conference, Manila, 2015 June (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Financial and Grant Records, 2001-2014; Series II
  - Financial records
    - Audits, 2010-2013 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Budgets and administrative records, 2007-2013 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Sample invoices, 2008-2010 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Sample requests to pay, 2004-2006 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Grants
    - FTE grants; documents and master copies (correspondence and financial documents), 2005-2014 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Indonesia grants, 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Malaysia grants, 2005-2006 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Myanmar grants (administrative records and correspondence), 2006 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Pakistan grants, 2005-2006 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Philippines grants, 2005-2006 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous grants, 2005-2008 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Publications, 1984-2017; Series III
  - FTE Newsletters
    - Issues 1-5, 2011-2013 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Issues 1-2 (2016); Issue 1 (2017), 2016-2017 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - FTE website
    - Printout of full site from 2015 March (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Printout of home page, photos 2016-2017 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Chinese Theological Review
    - CTR publications 22, 23, 24, and 25, 2010-2013 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - CTR correspondence, 1987-2006 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - CTR administrative records and correspondence, 1999-2014 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - CTR reports, 2010-2014 (Box 4, Folder 3-6)
  - Nanjing Theological Review
    - NTR correspondence and mailing lists (includes one CD), 1984-2007 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - History of FTE
    - Supporting Asian Christianity's Transition from Mission to Church, by Samuel C. Pearson (book), 2005 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Proposals and book/author recommendations - correspondence and written documents, 1997-2005 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Samuel C. Pearson contract, resume, and correspondence, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - FTESEA history contract, 1997-2005 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous documents - administrative correspondence and FTESEA history cover designs (includes two CDs), 2007-2010 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Partners and Related Organizations, 1953-2016; Series IV
  - ATEM
    - Correspondence, 2006-2011 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Financial documents, 2008-2010 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - General documents, 2007-2008 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Myanmar administrative documents (Ten-year faculty development project), 1990-2003 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Publications, no date (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - ATESEA
    - Administrative records, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence and documents (re: FTESEA chapter), 2005 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Financial documents, 2004-2008 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - General documents, 2008-2013 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - ATESEA general assembly, 2001 November (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Dr. Huang Po Ho: written reports and correspondence, 2007-2008 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - ATESEA general assembly, photos, Amity Round Table Meeting (including CD, DVDs), 2009, no date (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Officer's meeting/general assembly, 2013 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Publications, 2007-2012 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - ATESEA report, 2013 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - ATESEA resource commission: administrative and financial documents, 2002-2010 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - ATESEA newsletter, 2016 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - CCC/TSPM
    - DVD and brochure: "Protestant Church in China", 2003 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - China Bible exhibit, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - DVD: "A Lamp to my feet, A Light to my path" - Bible Ministry of the Protestant Churches in China, No date (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Itinerary and general documents from Trustees trip to China, 2003 March, October (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Nanjing Union Theological Seminary
    - Correspondence and grants, 1983-2009 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 2010-2012 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - History of Nanking Theological Seminary - 1911 to 1961, draft by Frank Wilson Price (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Legal documents regarding the NTS/education, 1956-2004 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Marvin Hoff "to-and-from" correspondence regarding the NTS, 1982-1996 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Financial records, 1955-1959 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Memorabilia and publications, 1953-2011 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Publications and pamphlets/60th anniversary media, 2005-2012 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Booklets from 60th anniversary and dedication of new campus, 2012 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - CD of hymns issued for 60th anniversary, 2012 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - NJUTS 60th anniversary Bible, 2012 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - NJUTS library, EBSCO database, 2006-2010 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - NJUTS library, financial records, 2007-2010 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - The North American Ecumenical Roundtable on China
    - NAERC documents - administrative records and written notes, 2002-2004 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - China visit reports - writings and correspondence, 2002-2008 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Pacific, Asian, and North American Asian Women in Theology and Ministry
    - PANAAWTM 17th annual conference schedule, 2002 April (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - World Council of Churches / Ecumenical Theological Education
    - Report regarding the Ecumenical Theological Education Programme and ETE projects and conferences, 2012 December (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Global Digital Library on Theology and Ecumenism (GlobeTheoLib) project, 2011-2015 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - ETE Program and Summary Reports, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Proposal for handbook on theological education, 2013 December (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Ecumenical Institute at Chateau de Bossey
    - Directories of alumni (compiled for FTE 75th anniversary), 2012 September 29 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- FTESEA Audio-Visual Materials, 2001-2011; Series V
  - FTESEA 75th anniversary DVD, 2012 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous photographs, no date (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Collected Material, 2001-2011; Series VI
  - Documents regarding Theological Education and Globalization, 2001-2011 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Documents regarding religion in China, 2004-2006 (Box 8, Folder 4)